Adoyiza Mark Salau || +2348145809102 || yiza29@yahoo.com

Frontend Web Developer

Professional Profile

I am a highly creative and career driven frontend developer with over 3 years work experience with a passion for creating user-friendly and responsive web applications. My achievements in various completed projects, timely delivery and client's satisfaction has brought about maximization of significant success working with different customers. I now seek to pursue my career by bringing my considerable experience and competencies to the contribution of new projects.

Skills and Competencies

Proficient in JavaScript, Typescript, Laravel Framework and React Framework

Expert in HTML/CSS/Bootstrap

Knowledge of UX/UI Design principles

Strong knowledge in Visual Studio code and components

Write neat readable codes

Web performance optimization

Proficient in GitHub and version control tools

Proficient in Database management and administration

Data modelling, cleaning and transformation

Data extraction, manipulation and analysis

Excellent communication skills

Excellent problem solving and debugging skills

Professional Experience

Frontend Web Developer

WynutCre8 Africa Ltd

Feb 2021 - till date

- Reviewed and remodified original websites code for a more friendly user-interface
- Maintenance of Company's website
- Provides updates on websites interface, raise concerns or challenges when needed
- Debug website bi-weekly to ensure no lag in the speed load when visited
- Uploaded modified website code to GitHub and created a repository for other co-developer to adjust its branches page and combined it for newer interface and improved functionality
- Collaborate with colleagues to share opinions and ideas on what changes needs to be done on website when there is a need.

Bridgegate Technologies

Aug 2019 – Jan 2021

Junior Software Developer

- Assisted the senior developer with the design, development, deployment and maintenance of all maintenance portal code using, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.
- Oversaw all content deployments for digital boards and management training systems.
- In charge of all maintenance and modification of all social media accounts
- Worked with the Backend team and learned about Data storage and its implementation in full stack web development

Data Analyst Intern

NYSC (Agege Local Government)

May 2018 - July 2019

- Provided support in ensuring that all data quality protocols are followed during data collection and cleaning to ensure the data is of the highest quality
- Assisted with drafting data collection tools
- Identified and reported any data issues, conducted detailed weekly reports, and pro-actively participated in team meetings with managers
- Assisted senior teams members in the data analysis process, contributing to a successful project that delivered impactful results to clients
- Collaborated with colleagues and executed other duties as assigned by managers
- Supported timely, quality research and business proposal submissions

Bridgegate Technologies

Nov 2017 - April 2018

IT Consultant Intern

- Assisted with organizing newly acquired computers for installations and programming
- Prepared, documented and implemented policies and procedures regarding IT systems and IT support
- Provided technical software, hardware and network problem resolution
- Assisted with the organization's communication needs to handle its social media outlets

Education

Olabisi Onabanjo University

May 2013- Oct 2017

Bachelors of Science (Statistics)

Certification

EarlyCode

March 2023-June2023

Web Development with Laravel

Relevant Projects: Finesse Salon and Spa

- Built a website for a client starting a Salon Business.
- Used languages such as JavaScript and Laravel framework, integrated with backend for data storage using MySQL
- Fully functional and responsive.